<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 20:28:33 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Walking to Work in the Rain</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-28-walking-to-work-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 20:28:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-28-walking-to-work-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while, I get to walk somewhere in the rain. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s just into the office at work, or into the grocery store. But a few minutes outside in the rain can be a wonderful time.
It&amp;rsquo;s not like driving where you&amp;rsquo;re warm and comfortable and insulated from the rain itself and only have to manage the windshield wipers. Walking in the rain let&amp;rsquo;s you experience a natural wonder no matter where you live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Evolution of Language</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-4-skibidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 21:10:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-4-skibidi/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a whole class of internet-based complaints about the current language used by, I think, middle schoolers of the moment. These complaints center around both newly invented words and existing words that have been assigned new meanings, interchangable with their old forms. The small-minded complainers take their outrage over these &amp;ldquo;brainrot&amp;rdquo; words to the internet, while the rest of us, if you&amp;rsquo;ve even heard a Gen-Alpha talk lately (I certainly haven&amp;rsquo;t), simply ignore them in the normal time-tested tradition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stoic Joy</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-6-30-a-stoic-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 18:37:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-6-30-a-stoic-joy/</guid>
      <description>Much of what I write is about books - I enjoy reading and learning from the lessons inside their stories. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing an observation, really just a perspective of the world I chanced upon.
We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last week in the Pocono Mountains, a rural and picturesque area of Pennsylvania sprinkled evenly with one-street coal towns and million-dollar resorts. The National Competition for the dance year is the main event; bottom-tier contestants cry as they run off stage after receiving an Elite Gold medal, and the best are awarded Premier Battle of Champions Crystal Trophies, Golden Tickets, Banners, and Pins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Exciting</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-5-6-something-exciting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 22:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-5-6-something-exciting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a huge amount of SciFi recently, and wanted to try writing my own original story with a brand new idea, with an Asimov-style twist at the end. Enjoy -
Joe opened his lunchbox and let the metal lid clink down on the workbench. Peanut butter and jelly, again. Certainly better than he had eaten during much of his time at the university, but not quite as exciting as he might wish for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything a Moonshot</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-4-2-everything-a-moonshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 23:30:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-4-2-everything-a-moonshot/</guid>
      <description>What if everything was a moonshot?
Nobody remembers anything small, so why do we bother? Small changes rarely have the desired impact, because we have compromised before ever starting the project. When we accept that doing &amp;ldquo;just this part&amp;rdquo; will be good enough, we are actively saying that we can indeed see the big picture, but don&amp;rsquo;t believe that either it&amp;rsquo;s possible or worthwhile to accomplish it. Given that it&amp;rsquo;s not worthwhile to accomplish the big-picture ask, should we even be attempting the scaled-down version?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating My Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-3-19-automating-my-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-3-19-automating-my-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on 2021-3-19 as an internal tech blog post when I was the Tech Lead for Wayfair&amp;rsquo;s Experimentation Platform team. Internal links will not work.
Automating my mistakes While building the initial steps of the GTQ project I found mysef stuck without a way to test code locally (at least without standing up a lot more project environment scaffolding), meaning that I had a slightly longer than ideal change/test loop:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Profiling with Python</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-1-26-python-memory-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-1-26-python-memory-profiling/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on 2021-1-26 as an internal tech blog post when I was the Tech Lead for Wayfair&amp;rsquo;s Experimentation Platform team. Internal links will not work.
Where I learn about memory profiling in Python We&amp;rsquo;ve observed that Simulations can fail when run in Kubernetes pods. We suspect the reason is that these pods are under-resourced and are running out of memory, then being killed/restarted by Kubernetes in order to keep the overall cluster healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disney Engineered</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-8-20-disney-engineered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 20:52:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-8-20-disney-engineered/</guid>
      <description>Besides world-class entertainment, immersive story-driven rides, and fine dining where you can eat filet mignon 3 times a day [1], the engineered efficiency of Disney World is absolutely top-tier. That makes it all the more fun to find situations that can be improved. Our most recent trip in August 2023 provided a few:
In order to enter the parks, you must scan either an RFID-based MagicBand(TM) which is like a digital watch without all the excitement, or an RFID-based card, which is like a Disney-branded RFID card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overpacking</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-5-20-overpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 22:41:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-5-20-overpacking/</guid>
      <description>Why do we like overpacking for trips so much?
I think it&amp;rsquo;s because the brain loves resets and new things - I think the brain actually loves getting good at new skills and environments much more than it enjoys being good at those same skills and in those same environments. The brain is near infinitely flexible and that&amp;rsquo;s its ultimate strength.
I just finished packing for a single weekend away. I wanted to bring a journal and necessary fountain pen, writing prompt book, a new nonfiction book to read, handheld amateur radio, laptop, camera gear, and Nintendo Switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other 8 Hours</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-1-10-the-other-8-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 23:03:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-1-10-the-other-8-hours/</guid>
      <description>In a quote that I can neither exactly remember nor find [1], in which some terribly heretical 19th-century socialist extolls the absurdity of limiting a work day to 8 hours, they also comment on the remaining 8 hours of leisure, rest, and relaxation time that each man has available at the end of the workday, and before the biologically required 8 hours of sleep. The main point is that every man is free to conduct himself exactly like the wealthy for those 8 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Emoji of Data</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</guid>
      <description>I recently spent some time thinking about how nice it is to be able to pay for gas a with a phone app from inside the car, the get out and start pumping immediately, no card swiping or buttons besides the big 89 needed. And once you&amp;rsquo;re done pumping, the app collects one single point of feeback data: you can click either the Smile, Meh, or Frown emoji.
Theoretically, something is being done with this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Inspiration from a Gas Station</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</guid>
      <description>In the past few years, Cumberland Farms has transformed themselves from a blue-and-orange gas station that you go to because you have to, into a blue-and-green (because you can reap the marketing rewards of the color green) gas station destination.
They did all this by changing the few things that people actually care about when it comes to gas stations. The stations now have a bright, modern design, with white walls and light wood floors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
