<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:42:50 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shadow of a Dark Queen</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:42:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</guid>
      <description>Shadow of a Dark Queen Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
The Serpentwar Saga is off to an unfortunate start: we follow a mercenary company as they sail around for a bit, march here, march over there, march up those mountains, march back down the slightly easier other side of the mountain, march into a town, march out of a town, march into a meeting of companies, march away from the other companies, march through a strange magical tunnel that turns out to have absolutely no bearing on the story&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of adventuring around in order to learn the super secret important information, but when the mission is completed, we&amp;rsquo;re not even included on what the secret info was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-6-apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-6-apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>As I sit down to write this, logging into Goodreads with a Facebook account hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked for 12 days. That seems like a fairly insane timeframe for an outage of this magnitude. But it also shows something else important. Amazon doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about Goodreads. Although that&amp;rsquo;s probably been obvious to the site&amp;rsquo;s users for some time, this puts a number on how low the priority stack ranking goes. After all, what percetage of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business is books anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
