<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book-reviews on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book-reviews on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rabbits</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-11-8-rabbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-11-8-rabbits/</guid>
      <description>Terry Miles
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
Apparently, I&amp;rsquo;m a total sucker for VR puzzles and mysteries that spill over into the real world. Rabbits captures the imagination in the same way as the beginnings of Ready Player One. This concept of a puzzle that starts online but escapes through the imagination of its players into real life is just mesmerizing. Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s thrillers The DaVinci Code and Digital Fortress are fun for the same feel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Body Problem</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-11-three-body-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 23:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-11-three-body-problem/</guid>
      <description>Cixin Liu
☆ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
I can&amp;rsquo;t even come close to understanding how this book won the Hugo award. Not only is it boring and difficult to follow in cultural translation, but it gets so many scientific facts wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s on these demerits that I shall rip the book apart. The Hugo medallion on the cover is the only reason I not only finished reading it, but then didn&amp;rsquo;t throw it directly in the trash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-2-atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:44:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-2-atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>James Clear
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
Atomic Habits easily gets 5 stars from me, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why it continually tops bestseller lists. It&amp;rsquo;s a fast and fun read with compelling and concrete examples. As I&amp;rsquo;m sure it was designed to, it inspires the reader to start working on new habits and recognize that their true power will be apparent only after the accumulation of a great many rounds of practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jesuit Guide to (Almost) Everything: A Spirituality for Real Life</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-26-jesuit-guide-to-almost-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 22:57:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-26-jesuit-guide-to-almost-everything/</guid>
      <description>James Martin
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book is a slog. It took weeks of forcing myself to return to it, and 400 pages to say nothing over and over again. The entire premise is that your life is better if you are &amp;ldquo;nearer&amp;rdquo; to God. &amp;ldquo;Nearness&amp;rdquo; is roughly defined as things that make your life &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; is roughly defined as defined as being everywhere, in all things and thoughts, and the solution to all issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tress of the Emerald Sea</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-14-tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 23:03:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-14-tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</guid>
      <description>Brandon Sanderson
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
Tress is easily one of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s best books, only Mistborn is in the same category. It combines a smart hero who learns and grows along the way with a fantastically new magic system (only 1/3 of which gets explored, sequals here we come!), incredibly witty dialogue, and a storyline that never feels slow or stale.
One of the main strengths of Tress the excellent characters and their dialogue; it&amp;rsquo;s realistic, snarky, and witty in the style of Good Omens, which Sanderson actually mentions as an inspiration in the author&amp;rsquo;s notes at the end of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy and the Crawler</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-30-jimmy-and-the-crawler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:04:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-30-jimmy-and-the-crawler/</guid>
      <description>Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
There&amp;rsquo;s nothing necissarily new or remarkable about this book, and that&amp;rsquo;s perfectly fine. Fans of Jimmy the Hand will thoroughly enjoy a return to Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s street-smart antics ranging from Krondor to Kesh.
There&amp;rsquo;s no Asimov Twist at the end like many of Feist&amp;rsquo;s books, but I&amp;rsquo;m still angry about the character he killed, and especially at the way it happened. I begrudgingly suppose that means the writing was immersive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Frugal Wizard&#39;s Handbook for Surviving Medieval England</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-15-frugal-wizards-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 23:03:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-15-frugal-wizards-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Brandon Sanderson
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book generally stinks. One of the large fatal flaws is usually a strength for Sanderson - the magic system of &amp;ldquo;boasts&amp;rdquo; consists of, as best I can tell because it&amp;rsquo;s not ever really explained, weird poems about how the boaster is great. The other, and totally disconnected, magic comes from the actions of wights who kindly perform exactly the correct task at exactly the correct time, for small offerings of fruits and nuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mona Lisa Overdrive</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-30-mona-lisa-overdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 22:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-30-mona-lisa-overdrive/</guid>
      <description>William Gibson
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
The only lucid page of this book is the last, where Gibson somehow pulls an amazing Asimov Twist from the wreckage of a great many useless characters, their useless locations, and nonexistent relationships. Of the 2 stars here, 1 of them is awarded to my own imagination for coming up with an amazing world that is sort of written about in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krondor: Tear of the Gods</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-20-krondor-tear-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:50:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-20-krondor-tear-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
Another great book starring Jimmy the Hand. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure anything can compare, for me, to spending the summer before 6th grade playing one of the earliest computer RPGs, and certainly the first 3D RPG I had played. But the book does a fair job of condensing an entire game into a shorter readtime than playtime.
The most interesting difference is the lack of immersion the book version provides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krondor: The Assassins</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-10-krondor-assassins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:57:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-10-krondor-assassins/</guid>
      <description>Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
The best part of this book is the character building. I know the characters of Return to Krondor well, and this gives deeper backstory and color to all of them, and others. Jimmy the Hand&amp;rsquo;s quick thinking and cleverness stars in both game and books, but we also get first hand stories of Arutha&amp;rsquo;s wisdom both in battle and court. We meet William for the first time and get to know a young soldier learning his place and forming his viewpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krondor: The Betrayal</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-30-krondor-betrayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 18:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-30-krondor-betrayal/</guid>
      <description>Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
The definition of a solid fantasy book without being a absolute smash hit. It&amp;rsquo;s a good book; just go read it.
Interestingly, this book was based on the Video Game Betrayal at Krondor, which I did not play, but sets up the plot for Tear of the Gods which is based on Return to Krondor, a game that I played the absolute heck out of the summer before 6th grade (1999).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ride of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-18-the-ride-of-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 21:45:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-18-the-ride-of-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>Robert Iger
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
This book is awesome because Iger talks about why things were hard, what he did to face the difficulties, and why those choices led to him being successful. He uses examples to color the ideas with story that draws you in, and neatly summarizes those ideas in ways that flow and teach. If you read this book through once and make an earnest attempt to learn anything from it, you&amp;rsquo;ll be a dozen leadership steps ahead of a certain billionaire I worked for (2022-2024).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ocean at the End of the Lane</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-1-the-ocean-at-the-end-of-the-lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 21:09:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-1-the-ocean-at-the-end-of-the-lane/</guid>
      <description>Neil Gaiman
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
My best description for this book is that it&amp;rsquo;s American Gods about kids. Most likely not for kids, unless the kids you know enjoy being terrified of all sorts of things being weird and wrong. I think the correct genre label for this book is actually horror. It thankfully didn&amp;rsquo;t give me nightmares or get me jumpy, but I know myself enough to know that I don&amp;rsquo;t care for horror; I&amp;rsquo;d rather experience something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neverwhere</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-18-neverwhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 22:18:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-18-neverwhere/</guid>
      <description>Neil Gaiman
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
Nobody writes hallucinations like Neil Gaiman; to my judgement, he&amp;rsquo;s the undisputed master. Neverwhere is another wonderful example of this ability, and takes the reader on a fast, weird, and wonderful journey into the opposite of a normal, common, place. That weirdness is exactly what makes the book so readable and enjoyable - you feel both comfortable with the common, but excited to see it in a new light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Productivity</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-11-slow-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 22:17:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-11-slow-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Cal Newport
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
First, the negatives, because there are few. The writing in this book is dry and academic, with the structure making it feel like you&amp;rsquo;re reading a series of 5-paragraph-essays from elementary school It tells instead of showing, and that slows the cadence of interest.
On the positive side, the message is both incredibly effective and simple:
Do fewer things. Work at a natural pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Princess Spy</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-27-the-princess-spy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 21:57:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-27-the-princess-spy/</guid>
      <description>Larry Loftis
☆ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
DID NOT FINISH, RECYCLED
This book successfully tricked me into trying it by using the word &amp;ldquo;Spy&amp;rdquo; in the title, but thouroughly failed at being readable shortly thereafter. The &amp;ldquo;spy&amp;rdquo; part of the book is glossed over rapidly, the protagonist attending CIA training and becoming an expert in thrilling skills such as firearms, encryption cyphers, and avoiding other agents, all in about 4 pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Moments</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-28-holy-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 21:57:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-28-holy-moments/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Kelly
★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
This book&amp;rsquo;s severe simplicity brings the readability down to, in my estimation, around an 6th grade level. The writing is pretty lackluster and boring, but the core messages are actually very solid. It just takes far too many pages to say too little about these ideas.
&amp;ldquo;Holy Moments&amp;rdquo; are first defined as when someone chooses to take a Good action instead of a Bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Town Living</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-10-ghost-town-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 22:23:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-10-ghost-town-living/</guid>
      <description>Brent Underwood
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
This book is a great fast and fun read, regardless of your familiarity with Brent&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel about living in Cerro Gordo. If you are already familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look behind the scenes into some of the details and off-camera hard work it has taken to start rebuilding a ghost town.
By far my favorite thing about the book however, is that Brent actually demonstrates what it looks like to live life as a Stoic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sofware Developer&#39;s Career Handbook</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-18-the-sofware-developers-career-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 17:01:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-18-the-sofware-developers-career-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Michael Lopp
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book suffers from an unfortunate case of being a product of a very specific time and set of circumstances. Moving from waterfall to agile, lunchtime card games, all-staff meetings, and working weekends to &amp;ldquo;ship&amp;rdquo; are all bygones in 2024. Originally written 10 years ago and just now supposedly updated then repackaged, the book does not hold up. Concrete lessons are few and far between, with the most helpful sections focusing on identifying the personalities of different players in the corporate game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightfall</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-5-nightfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 23:43:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-5-nightfall/</guid>
      <description>Isaac Asimov
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
One of the most impressive aspects of Asimov&amp;rsquo;s writing is that it can change your worldview in just a few pages of a short story. When the twist at the end makes you rethink how the universe works, the writing comes alive off the page.
The Nightfall anthology is great for 2 reasons. It covers a huge range of topics, styles, and story sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Superlatives</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-1-25-2023-superlatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 22:48:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-1-25-2023-superlatives/</guid>
      <description>For the first time, probably ever, I think I actually own all the books I read in the previous year. So while I enjoy ranking books, among other things, doing it physically is a fun twist!
If I had to place a dividing line, I&amp;rsquo;d put only the top 4, The Deep Range and above, into my &amp;ldquo;highly recommended&amp;rdquo; list for the year. I&amp;rsquo;m proud of myself for trying such a wide range of books, but in the future I would rather increse the percentage of books that I really enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like a Monk</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-17-think-like-a-monk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 22:58:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-17-think-like-a-monk/</guid>
      <description>Jay Shetty
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book took me probably 6 months to finish. I picked it up several times, but struggled to find it interesting enough to finish and frequently moved on to a new book. I would have greatly preferred to simply read stories about Shetty&amp;rsquo;s time in the ashram, and how he applies those lessons to modern life.
It sits at the intersection of productive self-improvement and philosophy, so ostensibly a very interesting subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-12-the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 22:22:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-12-the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>Ursula K. LeGuin
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book really sucks. Mostly for the completely wasted opportunities of fairly good ideas. A world too cold for insects and animals larger than a dog to survive, yet with still active volcanic zones. People who are both genders. Explorers from worlds light years away making contact with primitive humans and bringing them into a universal community. Actually, that last one had a documentary about it called Stargate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Slow Regard of Silent Things</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-30-the-slow-regard-of-silent-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 07:50:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-30-the-slow-regard-of-silent-things/</guid>
      <description>The Slow Regard of Silent Things Patrick Rothfuss
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
I&amp;rsquo;m going to start listening to any book that opens with &amp;ldquo;You might not want to read this book.&amp;rdquo; The problem is that I really did want to read this book, or at least the story that I thought it would be great if it contained. I wanted to read about how Auri came to be who she is and live where she does, and why her view of the world is shaped the way it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wise Mans Fear</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-11-the-wise-mans-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 22:10:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-11-the-wise-mans-fear/</guid>
      <description>The Wise Man&amp;rsquo;s Fear Patrick Rothfuss
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
As I read Fantasy and Sci-Fi books, I like to take note of particular writing methods and distill them into themes that can be harnessed when doing my own writing. These themes of course can be split into &amp;ldquo;emulate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;avoid&amp;rdquo;. The Wise Man&amp;rsquo;s Fear is gracious enough to provide one of each.
In-Universe Complex Context Reload
Starting off with the &amp;ldquo;emulate&amp;rdquo; column, as a sequal, this book is responsible for bringing you back into Kvothe&amp;rsquo;s world of the Four Corners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Name of the Wind</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-9-16-the-name-of-the-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:15:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-9-16-the-name-of-the-wind/</guid>
      <description>The Name of the Wind Patrick Rothfuss
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
At almost 700 pages, this is far from the longest book I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read, but I read it faster than some books 1/3 it&amp;rsquo;s size. Perhaps an even greater compliment is the several times I stayed up hours late reading to finish the story.
The story itself is actually nothing all that earth-shattering: our hero is orphaned as a young boy, learns hard lessons on the street, finds himself clever enough to make it to the magical University, and then excells in lessons, while causing a fair amount of trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Omens</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-8-30-good-omens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:05:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-8-30-good-omens/</guid>
      <description>Good Omens Neil Gaiman and Terry Pratchett
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
I&amp;rsquo;ve never been the antagonist of a book before, but it turns out to be pretty fun. When a logical argument can be made for the representatives of both Heaven and Hell to work together because the real problem is those pesky humans, the result is a golden story. The best part is that the relationship between an angel and demon turns out incredibly naturally, perhaps because they both borrow so much of their personalities from those same flawed humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Metal</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-25-the-lost-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:11:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-25-the-lost-metal/</guid>
      <description>The Lost Metal Brandon Sanderson ★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
Reading this book strongly reinforces the importance of approaching a series in order, and ideally without interruption. In this case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t, and the experience suffered for it. I had read the first book in the series, unknowingly skipped the second two, and picked up this book as the 4th because I knew I enjoyed the author and series. The problem is that significant plot points and items are discussed as if they are common knowledge, because to the characters they are, but I had to piece them together with very limited context clues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-1-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 21:55:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-1-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>Red Team Blues Cory Doctrow
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
This book is a fun, quick, and entertaining read, but the best part is that it&amp;rsquo;s a techno-thriller that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get anything wrong. Although this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the accomplishment that it is, not getting any technical details wrong really is quite notable. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly complaining that an author decided to include detail they didn&amp;rsquo;t need to, and then got some part of that detail wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leviathan Wakes</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-6-12-leviathan-wakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:09:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-6-12-leviathan-wakes/</guid>
      <description>Leviathan Wakes James S. A. Corey
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure out why this book was 600 pages long. There&amp;rsquo;s not a huge amount of action, intrigue, and certainly not suspense. Oh, except that GRRM blurbed the cover and the proles think he&amp;rsquo;s the only fiction author to ever exist, despite ample evidence that he&amp;rsquo;s both a terrible and lazy writer.
Characters and places are described directly, but in the wrong sort of way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Park</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-4-30-jurassic-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:54:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-4-30-jurassic-park/</guid>
      <description>Jurassic Park Michael Chrichton
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
I somehow made it through the 90s without ever seeing Jurassic Park the movie, so when I found a paperback copy of Jurassic Park the book at the Northborough Library Book Sale, I figured this was my opportunity to do it the right way.
Read the book first, then watch the movie.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always known that dinosaurs are just about the coolest creatures ever, and Tyrannosaurus king among them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Sniper</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-3-15-american-sniper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:53:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-3-15-american-sniper/</guid>
      <description>American Sniper Chris Kyle
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
Some subjects are always worth learning about, even if they&amp;rsquo;re not personally interesting, generally interesting, or have any redeeming qualities whatsoever. These subjects demand at least some attention from any learned mind, even if the only lessons are in their awfulness, responsibility, or consequences. A few books about the Holocaust come to mind, especially Night by Eli Wiesel. There is nothing good about the subject, but learning and understanding it teaches the reader about an awful part of the world so that we may understand and avoid it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Deep Range</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-30-the-deep-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:53:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-30-the-deep-range/</guid>
      <description>The Deep Range Arthur C. Clark
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
This book is classic Sci-Fi at it&amp;rsquo;s best - a plucky protagonist with a few more smarts and skills than average takes on a new mission, a mission that he succeeds at in fact, until the pivotal brain-bending twist that forces you to step back and think &amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo;.
This &amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo; moment is my favorite thing about Sci-Fi, and to me, the facet that defines it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agency</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-15-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:05:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-15-agency/</guid>
      <description>Agency William Gibson
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of books with lots of overly-specific brand names where the protagonist is just along for the ride, only participates by presence, and does nothing to affect their own outcome in the story, then boy howdy this book is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Lives of Color</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 23:04:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</guid>
      <description>The Secret Lives of Color Kassia St Clair
★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
I think I read this book incorrectly. I approached it in the usual manner; starting at the front, making progress one page at a time, until all pages have been turned in order. Progress was measured in groups of 10-20 pages, covering the stories of 2-5 individual colors at a time.
There are other valid methods however, and it seems a wise reminder to not automatically approach every scenario with only the exact techniques that have worked in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow of a Dark Queen</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:42:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</guid>
      <description>Shadow of a Dark Queen Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
The Serpentwar Saga is off to an unfortunate start: we follow a mercenary company as they sail around for a bit, march here, march over there, march up those mountains, march back down the slightly easier other side of the mountain, march into a town, march out of a town, march into a meeting of companies, march away from the other companies, march through a strange magical tunnel that turns out to have absolutely no bearing on the story&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of adventuring around in order to learn the super secret important information, but when the mission is completed, we&amp;rsquo;re not even included on what the secret info was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ender&#39;s Game</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-enders-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-enders-game/</guid>
      <description>Orson Scott Card
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game does several sci-fi-book things correctly. The setup requires you to suspend disbelief, invented terms are used well, and the story continues after the climax to a satisfying result that is both an ending and a possible sequel setup.
A good sci-fi book asks the reader to suspend disbelief about some, possibly very important, statements given as facts. The story beginning with Ender as a six-year-old makes no sense whatever, especially when his voice and actions would be a better match for a mature 20-something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Wild</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-into-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-into-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>Jon Krakauer ★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
The writing is fine. The storyline of the book is fine. What&amp;rsquo;s not fine is Chris McCandless&amp;rsquo;s lame vagabondry - a series of poorly-at-best thought through decisions can be defended only by the ambiguous &amp;ldquo;call of the wild&amp;rdquo;. Despite several starting advantages in life, McCandless decides to spend his life on the road for no reason other than a desire for &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; that only he can understand yet cannot express or communicate to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prince of the Blood</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-prince-of-the-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-prince-of-the-blood/</guid>
      <description>Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
You could equally hand this book to a new reader of high fantasy or to a longtime fan of the genre and the Riftwar, and they would both be impressed and excited throughout the length of the story. Focusing on Prince Arutha&amp;rsquo;s sons journey to Kesh and their own maturity, Jimmy the Hand takes a significant supporting role as mentor and conspirator of Arutha&amp;rsquo;s stunning last-page twist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REAMDE</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-reamde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-reamde/</guid>
      <description>Neal Stephenson
DID NOT FINISH
The score of &amp;ldquo;DID NOT FINISH&amp;rdquo; is reserved for books so incredibly offensive that completing them is a net negative on time investment. Rarely is it possible to have your intelligence reduced by reading, although certain books make the possibility clear. I made it to page 139 out of 1044 (13.3%).
In REAMDE, Stephenson falls into, in my opinion, the most basic mistake a writer, especially of science fiction, can make: insisting on an incredibly detailed world and then getting those details wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronauts Guide to Life on Earth</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-astronauts-guide-to-life-on-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-astronauts-guide-to-life-on-earth/</guid>
      <description>Chris Hadfield
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
When I read nonfiction, instead of taking notes in the moment, I take a picture of the salient passage and transcribe them later. The stories Commander Hadfield shares are incredibly interesting and well told, but the sheer number of pithy lessons that I found myself returning to undoubtedly rank this book very highly.
On Preparation:
In my experience, fear comes from not knowing what to expect and not feeling you have any control over what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coraline</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-coraline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-coraline/</guid>
      <description>Neil Gaiman
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
This book is weird, in the great way that Neil Gaiman excells at. Thouroughly enjoyable, I read this over the course of two afternoons. Some years ago, I spent days reading American Gods - and although they are both weird in a similar and excellent sort of way, Coraline was a much faster, simpler, experince, and refreshing for it. Elements of the simplicity and directness that quickly advance the story are strong positive influences that I&amp;rsquo;ll use for myself in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Minimalism</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-digital-minimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-digital-minimalism/</guid>
      <description>Cal Newport
★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
This book builds on the consistent themes of Professor Newport&amp;rsquo;s work - that in our new attention economy, your time is your most precious resource, and protecting it from digital distractions is exceedingly and increasingly difficult, because millions of the smartest mind-hours are devoted to depriving you of it for their own profit.
In defense of this onslaught, high-quality leisure undertaken solely for the satisifaction of it&amp;rsquo;s completion provides a significant mental fortress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dune Messiah</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-dune-messiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-dune-messiah/</guid>
      <description>Frank Herbert
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
Nothing really happens in this entire book. Paul Maud&amp;rsquo;Dib antagonizes himself with the ability to see the future, yet somehow do nothing about his own predestination. Instead of a storyline, the book skips around to follow the fleeting thoughts of several characters and their current feelings towards one another; the definition of a Space Opera, in the worst way. The conflict is stated instead of shown, and the fascinating future-historic technology of Dune is almost entirely missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy the Hand</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-jimmy-the-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-jimmy-the-hand/</guid>
      <description>Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s signature cleverness is used to great effect both causing and getting out of trouble in a series of adventures, where the reader gets to know more inner workings of the Thieves Guild. A parallel storyline details events touched upon in the main Riftwar Saga. This is the main drawback of the book; Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s adventures are second to none, yet half the book is spent following others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Peripheral</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-the-peripheral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-the-peripheral/</guid>
      <description>William Gibson
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
The protagonist of this book is a bystander to the story, and to a minor character&amp;rsquo;s conflict. She does nothing to advance the story, and barely participates in it. This is either one of the greatest examples of &amp;ldquo;being nothing but a pawn in a game for higher beings&amp;rdquo;, or a very disjointed way of telling a story; I&amp;rsquo;m very much not sure which is true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-6-apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-6-apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>As I sit down to write this, logging into Goodreads with a Facebook account hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked for 12 days. That seems like a fairly insane timeframe for an outage of this magnitude. But it also shows something else important. Amazon doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about Goodreads. Although that&amp;rsquo;s probably been obvious to the site&amp;rsquo;s users for some time, this puts a number on how low the priority stack ranking goes. After all, what percetage of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business is books anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
