<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 21:55:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 7 1 Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-7-1-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 21:55:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-7-1-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>Red Team Blues Cory Doctrow ★ ★ ★ ★ ★
This book is a fun, quick, and entertaining read, but the best part is that it&amp;rsquo;s a techno-thriller that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get anything wrong. Although this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the accomplishment that it is, not getting any technical details wrong really is quite notable. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly complaining that an author decided to include detail they didn&amp;rsquo;t need to, and then got some part of that wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disney Engineered</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-8-20-disney-engineered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 20:52:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-8-20-disney-engineered/</guid>
      <description>Besides world-class entertainment, immersive story-driven rides, and fine dining where you can eat filet mignon 3 times a day [1], the engineered efficiency of Disney World is absolutely top-tier. That makes it all the more fun to find situations that can be improved. Our most recent trip in August 2023 provided a few:
In order to enter the parks, you must scan either an RFID-based MagicBand(TM) which is like a digital watch without all the excitement, or an RFID-based card, which is like a Disney-branded RFID card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leviathan Wakes</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-6-12-leviathan-wakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:09:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-6-12-leviathan-wakes/</guid>
      <description>Leviathan Wakes James S. A. Corey
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure out why this book was 600 pages long. There&amp;rsquo;s not a huge amount of action, intrigue, and certainly not suspense. Oh, except that GRRM blurbed the cover and the proles think he&amp;rsquo;s the only fiction author to ever exist, despite ample evidence that he&amp;rsquo;s both a terrible and lazy writer.
Characters and places are described directly, but in the wrong sort of way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overpacking</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-5-20-overpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 22:41:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-5-20-overpacking/</guid>
      <description>Why do we like overpacking for trips so much?
I think it&amp;rsquo;s because the brain loves resets and new things - I think the brain actually loves getting good at new skills and environments much more than it enjoys being good at those same skills and in those same environments. The brain is near infinitely flexible and that&amp;rsquo;s its ultimate strength.
I just finished packing for a single weekend away. I wanted to bring a journal and necessary fountain pen, writing prompt book, a new nonfiction book to read, handheld amateur radio, laptop, camera gear, and Nintendo Switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Park</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-4-30-jurassic-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:54:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-4-30-jurassic-park/</guid>
      <description>Jurassic Park Michael Chrichton
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
I somehow made it through the 90s without ever seeing Jurassic Park the movie, so when I found a paperback copy of Jurassic Park the book at the Northborough Library Book Sale, I figured this was my opportunity to do it the right way.
Read the book first, then watch the movie.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always known that dinosaurs are just about the coolest creatures ever, and Tyrannosaurus king among them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Sniper</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-3-15-american-sniper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:53:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-3-15-american-sniper/</guid>
      <description>American Sniper Chris Kyle
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
Some subjects are always worth learning about, even if they&amp;rsquo;re not personally interesting, generally interesting, or have any redeeming qualities whatsoever. These subjects demand at least some attention from any learned mind, even if the only lessons are in their awfulness, responsibility, or consequences. A few books about the Holocaust come to mind, especially Night by Eli Wiesel. There is nothing good about the subject, but learning and understanding it teaches the reader about an awful part of the world so that we may understand and avoid it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Deep Range</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-30-the-deep-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:53:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-30-the-deep-range/</guid>
      <description>The Deep Range Arthur C. Clark
★ ★ ★ ★ ☆
This book is classic Sci-Fi at it&amp;rsquo;s best - a plucky protagonist with a few more smarts and skills than average takes on a new mission, a mission that he succeeds at in fact, until the pivotal brain-bending twist that forces you to step back and think &amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo;.
This &amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo; moment is my favorite thing about Sci-Fi, and to me, the facet that defines it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agency</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-15-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:05:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-15-agency/</guid>
      <description>Agency William Gibson
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of books with lots of overly-specific brand names where the protagonist is just along for the ride, only participates by presence, and does nothing to affect their own outcome in the story, then boy howdy this book is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Lives of Color</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 23:04:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</guid>
      <description>The Secret Lives of Color Kassia St Clair
★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
I think I read this book incorrectly. I approached it in the usual manner; starting at the front, making progress one page at a time, until all pages have been turned in order. Progress was measured in groups of 10-20 pages, covering the stories of 2-5 individual colors at a time.
There are other valid methods however, and it seems a wise reminder to not automatically approach every scenario with only the exact techniques that have worked in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other 8 Hours</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-1-10-the-other-8-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 23:03:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-1-10-the-other-8-hours/</guid>
      <description>In a quote that I can neither exactly remember nor find, in which some terribly heretical 19th-century socialist extolls the absurdity of limiting a work day to 8 hours, they also comment on the remaining 8 hours of leisure, rest, and relaxation time that each man has available at the end of the workday, and before the biologically required 8 hours of sleep. The main point is that every man is free to conduct himself exactly like the wealthy for those 8 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow of a Dark Queen</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:42:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</guid>
      <description>Shadow of a Dark Queen Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
The Serpentwar Saga is off to an unfortunate start: we follow a mercenary company as they sail around for a bit, march here, march over there, march up those mountains, march back down the slightly easier other side of the mountain, march into a town, march out of a town, march into a meeting of companies, march away from the other companies, march through a strange magical tunnel that turns out to have absolutely no bearing on the story&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of adventuring around in order to learn the super secret important information, but when the mission is completed, we&amp;rsquo;re not even included on what the secret info was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Reading</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-9-3-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-9-3-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>Prince of the Blood Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
You could equally hand this book to a new reader of high fantasy or to a longtime fan of the genre and the Riftwar, and they would both be impressed and excited throughout the length of the story. Focusing on Prince Arutha&amp;rsquo;s sons journey to Kesh and their own maturity, Jimmy the Hand takes a significant supporting role as mentor and conspirator of Arutha&amp;rsquo;s stunning last-page twist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Reading</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-8-6-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 22:33:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-8-6-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>As I sit down to write this, logging into Goodreads with a Facebook account hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked for 12 days. That seems like a fairly insane timeframe for an outage of this magnitude. But it also shows something else important. Amazon doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about Goodreads. Although that&amp;rsquo;s probably been obvious to the site&amp;rsquo;s users for some time, this puts a number on how low the priority stack ranking goes. After all, what percetage of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business is books anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Emoji of Data</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</guid>
      <description>I recently spent some time thinking about how nice it is to be able to pay for gas a with a phone app from inside the car, the get out and start pumping immediately, no card swiping or buttons besides the big 89 needed. And once you&amp;rsquo;re done pumping, the app collects one single point of feeback data: you can click either the Smile, Meh, or Frown emoji.
Theoretically, something is being done with this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Inspiration from a Gas Station</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</guid>
      <description>In the past few years, Cumberland Farms has transformed themselves from a blue-and-orange gas station that you go to because you have to, into a blue-and-green (because you can reap the marketing rewards of the color green) gas station destination.
They did all this by changing the few things that people actually care about when it comes to gas stations. The stations now have a bright, modern design, with white walls and light wood floors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
