<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:05:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agency</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-15-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:05:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-15-agency/</guid>
      <description>Agency William Gibson
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of books with lots of overly-specific brand names where the protagonist is just along for the ride, only participates by presence, and does nothing to affect their own outcome in the story, then boy howdy this book is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Lives of Color</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 23:04:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</guid>
      <description>The Secret Lives of Color Kassia St Clair ★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
I think I read this book incorrectly. I approached it in the usual manner; starting at the front, making progress one page at a time, until all pages have been turned in order. Progress was measured in groups of 10-20 pages, covering the stories of 2-5 individual colors at a time.
There are other valid methods however, and it seems a wise reminder to not automatically approach every scenario with only the exact techniques that have worked in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow of a Dark Queen</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:42:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</guid>
      <description>Shadow of a Dark Queen Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
The Serpentwar Saga is off to an unfortunate start: we follow a mercenary company as they sail around for a bit, march here, march over there, march up those mountains, march back down the slightly easier other side of the mountain, march into a town, march out of a town, march into a meeting of companies, march away from the other companies, march through a strange magical tunnel that turns out to have absolutely no bearing on the story&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of adventuring around in order to learn the super secret important information, but when the mission is completed, we&amp;rsquo;re not even included on what the secret info was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Reading</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-9-3-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-9-3-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>Prince of the Blood Raymond E. Feist
★ ★ ★ ★ ★
You could equally hand this book to a new reader of high fantasy or to a longtime fan of the genre and the Riftwar, and they would both be impressed and excited throughout the length of the story. Focusing on Prince Arutha&amp;rsquo;s sons journey to Kesh and their own maturity, Jimmy the Hand takes a significant supporting role as mentor and conspirator of Arutha&amp;rsquo;s stunning last-page twist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Reading</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-8-6-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 22:33:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2022-8-6-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>As I sit down to write this, logging into Goodreads with a Facebook account hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked for 12 days. That seems like a fairly insane timeframe for an outage of this magnitude. But it also shows something else important. Amazon doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about Goodreads. Although that&amp;rsquo;s probably been obvious to the site&amp;rsquo;s users for some time, this puts a number on how low the priority stack ranking goes. After all, what percetage of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business is books anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Emoji of Data</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</guid>
      <description>I recently spent some time thinking about how nice it is to be able to pay for gas a with a phone app from inside the car, the get out and start pumping immediately, no card swiping or buttons besides the big 89 needed. And once you&amp;rsquo;re done pumping, the app collects one single point of feeback data: you can click either the Smile, Meh, or Frown emoji.
Theoretically, something is being done with this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Inspiration from a Gas Station</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</guid>
      <description>In the past few years, Cumberland Farms has transformed themselves from a blue-and-orange gas station that you go to because you have to, into a blue-and-green (because you can reap the marketing rewards of the color green) gas station destination.
They did all this by changing the few things that people actually care about when it comes to gas stations. The stations now have a bright, modern design, with white walls and light wood floors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
