<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 22:58:06 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023-12-17 Think Like a Monk</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-12-17-think-like-a-monk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 22:58:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-12-17-think-like-a-monk/</guid>
      <description>Jay Shetty
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book took me probably 6 months to finish. I picked it up several times, but struggled to find it interesting enough to finish and frequently moved on to a new book. I would have greatly preferred to simply read stories about Shetty&amp;rsquo;s time in the ashram, and how he applies those lessons to modern life.
It sits at the intersection of productive self-improvement and philosophy, so ostensibly a very interesting subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-12-12-the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 22:22:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-12-12-the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>Ursula K. LeGuin
★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆
This book really sucks. Mostly for the completely wasted opportunities of fairly good ideas. A world too cold for insects and animals larger than a dog to survive, yet with still active volcanic zones. People who are both genders. Explorers from worlds light years away making contact with primitive humans and bringing them into a universal community. Actually, that last one had a documentary about it called Stargate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Slow Regard of Silent Things</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-10-30-the-slow-regard-of-silent-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 07:50:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/posts/2023-10-30-the-slow-regard-of-silent-things/</guid>
      <description>The Slow Regard of Silent Things Patrick Rothfuss
★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆
I&amp;rsquo;m going to start listening to any book that opens with &amp;ldquo;You might not want to read this book.&amp;rdquo; The problem is that I really did want to read this book, or at least the story that I thought it would be great if it contained. I wanted to read about how Auri came to be who she is and live where she does, and why her view of the world is shaped the way it is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
