<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Victor Jacek</title>
    <link>https://vjacek.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Victor Jacek</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vjacek.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>User Manual</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2025-11-23-usermanual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2025-11-23-usermanual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The company I work for was recently sold from one private equity group to another private equity group. While I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are significant changes coming, the new executives have started their tenure not by handing down directives, but by listening and gathering input. One of the ways they are doing this was to ask the Leadership Team (Senior Directors and Distinguished Engineers) to complete a &amp;ldquo;User Manual&amp;rdquo; exercise. Two of those people in my group were kind enough to share their own manuals and inspire this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Fire Upon the Deep</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-11-22-a-fire-upon-the-deep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-11-22-a-fire-upon-the-deep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vernor Vinge&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DID NOT FINISH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book was so incredibly dumb and boring that I had to go back to reading &lt;em&gt;Walden&lt;/em&gt;. Which is an amazing book, but not exactly a Sci Fi thriller.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hate books where the first &amp;ldquo;protagonist&amp;rdquo; is killed immediately. It&amp;rsquo;s not clever or interesting or new. It&amp;rsquo;s a let down to the reader and leaves them searching for a reason to care about anything in the book, since you&amp;rsquo;ve just shown that the first thing they tried to care about wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually important. You&amp;rsquo;re telling the reader &amp;ldquo;no you&amp;rsquo;re wrong&amp;rdquo; right away instead of leading them on a journey of discovery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Useful - Seven Tools for Life</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-10-13-be-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-10-13-be-useful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arnold Schwarzenegger&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is great because it&amp;rsquo;s both deep but plainly written. I have found that the most true ideas are the only ones that can stand up to such pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Arnold takes responsibility for mistakes, he does it straight up. No but-this-or-that or the-other-thing excuses. Just a man trying his best, acknowledging when he falls short, and trying to improve. I have incredible respect for that approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altered Carbon</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-9-30-altered-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-9-30-altered-carbon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Richard Morgan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DID NOT FINISH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is absolute trash masquerading as Sci Fi so that semi-literate yet horny frat bros can pretend they&amp;rsquo;ve read a book once in their adult lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worst thing is that the primary Sci Fi concept of having your conciousness digitized and &amp;ldquo;resleeved&amp;rdquo; into a new body when you die actually has some merit, or could in someone else&amp;rsquo;s hands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The final straw for me was when the protagonist uses a &amp;ldquo;termite grenade&amp;rdquo;. Yes, a grenade apparently made out of small bugs who enjoy eating wood. I can only assume the author meant &amp;ldquo;thermite&amp;rdquo;, such a lame incendiary choice that pumpkin spice lattes call it basic. First, that&amp;rsquo;s just sloppy editing. Second, it&amp;rsquo;s sloppy writing. Third, it&amp;rsquo;s stupid writing because as anyone with a cool 10th-grade science teacher knows, thermite burns very nicely but does not explode. A thermite grenade would sit there and quietly melt itself into the ground while everyone watches. In fact, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5uxsFglz2ig&#34;&gt;how they weld train tracks together&lt;/a&gt;. And those dudes barely even engaged their safety squints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fragile Things</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-9-4-fragile-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-9-4-fragile-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DID NOT FINISH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well that was unfortunate, I guess I understand why Neil got himself canceled now. I found book to be marginally better than doomscrolling your phone while riding the commuter rail out of Boston at 5pm on a Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the stories are stories about telling stories. This &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be pretty interesting, the meta-stories were mostly pretty good, but the internal stories were mostly pretty lousy. They didn&amp;rsquo;t have purposes, meanings, or in many cases resolutions. One particular meta-story laments the problem of not having a story-shaped story to tell. That turns out to be indeed quite the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solaris</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-8-28-solaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-8-28-solaris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanislaw Lem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best that can be said for this book is that it distinctly crosses the line between sci-fi and horror. It&amp;rsquo;s more of an exploration of one man&amp;rsquo;s mental fears as of the novel planet it takes place on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That planet provides both the setting and antagonist, but neither is really done in a complete way. Not until the last few pages does the protagonist venture outside of the enclosed station and actually interact with the planet. And for all the time the protagonist spends with the totally-not-antagonistic apparition created by the supposedly-antagonistic planet, he mostly ignores the apparition while fretting about why it&amp;rsquo;s there. No real action takes place, just a lot of mental anguish similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-dune-messiah/&#34;&gt;Dune Messiah&lt;/a&gt;. Even when the protagonist attempts to interact with the 2 other humans on the station, they simply refuse to interact or share their own problems. Maybe this is likely reflective of reality, but wow is it boring to read about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starship Troopers</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-8-10-starship-troopers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-8-10-starship-troopers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert A. Heinlein&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heinlein really had it it for democracy, which is great because democracy sucks. Here in 2025 it&amp;rsquo;s become abundantly clear that democracy has failed in the United States, and we&amp;rsquo;ve now got a front row seat to the slow but inevitable downfall. Heinlein absolutely nails two of the most important reasons why democracy in our form is doomed:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We ask the impossible from our government and get upset when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Voters must be willing to put &amp;ldquo;the group&amp;rdquo; ahead of themselves. Which is impossible in heterogenous a group this large.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I remember being assigned to argue for Federalism in A.P. U.S. History class in high school. At the time it seemed to make sense, unifying the States would give the country the ability to defend itself both militarily and economically from much more established nations, while not sapping it&amp;rsquo;s own strength by punative disagreements with it&amp;rsquo;s closest neighbors (the other states). In 2025, the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m burdoned by high taxes in Massachusetts which are federally redistributed to other states makes much less sense. A federal goverment burdoned by the mission of writing laws for such a hugely diverse nation has little chance of success. Maybe it would indeed be better for those of similar ideals to congregate together and govern themselves; we&amp;rsquo;d get exactly what we ask for, and potentially what we deserve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Fixed Temperature</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2025-7-25-i-fixed-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2025-7-25-i-fixed-temperature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All 3 temperature systems [1], [2] have some major problems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kelvin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Astronomically, the Kelvin scale makes a lot of sense. Given the vast general emptiness of space, you might have a pretty reasonable need to use the low end of the spectrum, and absolute zero is a wonderful place to start. But for temperatures that humans might experience, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty far off from the Most Useful Numbers (0-100).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celcius&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we move to Celcius, we lose absolute truth at absolute zero, and make the critical improvement of becoming based on water, the Most Important Molecule. For humans, nothing could make more sense than basing our discussion and measurements around water, upon which our existence is already naturally based. The problem is that we don&amp;rsquo;t get to use very much of the scale in everyday life. You might be able to experience the range from -25C to 45C in a lifetime, but that&amp;rsquo;s only a total difference of 70 degrees. In common usage, 10C would be considered cool, and 27C warm. This gives an absolutely pathetic resolution of 17 degrees! The difference of a degree is so large that decimal points become common. This silliness must be another major reason the United States has not largely adopted Celcius.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surely You&#39;re Joking Mr. Feynman</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-7-15-surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-7-15-surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frequently hilarious and sharply insightful, Feynman&amp;rsquo;s autobiography is wonderful reading all the way through. They way he approaches problems of both personal and technical natures is one that more people should emulate. Fenyman&amp;rsquo;s constant curiosity, along with a penchant for trouble, are the golden threads weaving throughout his life, again in both personal and technical realms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This theme of curiosity and desire to explore new fields is something I really enjoy emulating - for all his scientific and mental prowress, Feynman was perfectly happy to walk into a room as the person knowing the least and ask questions, poke and prod the subect, until he actually &lt;em&gt;understood&lt;/em&gt; it; grokked it, in the true definition of the word. In this same way, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that I love learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Invisibility</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-7-4-the-art-of-invisibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-7-4-the-art-of-invisibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mitnick&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DID NOT FINISH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought this book without thinking or even skimming a few pages because Mitnick&amp;rsquo;s first book &lt;em&gt;The Art of Deception&lt;/em&gt; was one of the first life-changing books I had ever read. It detailed the fascinating stories of hackers who used social engineering to gain access to people, places, and things that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have. &lt;em&gt;The Art of Invisibility&lt;/em&gt; unfortunately couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every Tool&#39;s a Hammer</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-6-30-every-tool-a-hammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-6-30-every-tool-a-hammer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Savage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the world&amp;rsquo;s foremost builders, creatives, inventors, problem-solvers, or as he describes himself, Maker, Adam Savage is the right person to listen to when it comes to building stuff. He&amp;rsquo;s done it. A lot of it. So this book holds incredible weight of informed opinion. Savage details a few successes and failures throughout the book&amp;rsquo;s topics, those stories form an awesome backbone for exploring a great set of wide-ranging topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stranger in a Strange Land</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-6-15-stranger-in-a-strange-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-6-15-stranger-in-a-strange-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert A. Heinlein&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book starts as a fascinating exploration of how a human raised on Mars would have trouble adjusting to life among Earthlings, takes a hairpin turn into the construction of a utopian free-love cult, and yet still triumphantly manages to leave you thinking for days and days after finishing the last page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very best sci-fi leaves you in this pondering state across your daily life. In the case of &lt;em&gt;The Deep Range&lt;/em&gt;, you &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; yet disprove the theory that keeps you thinking. In the case of &lt;em&gt;Stranger in a Strange Land&lt;/em&gt;, I believe I can. The offered premise is that anything that groks is itself God. Therefore bugs, animals, and all people are God. But if we are to grok that grok is a level of understanding so perfect as to merge your thoughts with that which you grok, I argue that bugs, animals, and many people are actually incapable of that. Those lower lifeforms respond to stimuli, preserve and reproduce themselves, but have no ability to plan for the future and modify their environment in a way that optimizes their enjoyment or self-actualization. That seems like a decent discrimination between grokking and non-grokking lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origins of the Wheel of Time</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-5-1-origins-of-the-wheel-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-5-1-origins-of-the-wheel-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Livingston&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I quite enjoyed the first third of this book, where we learn about Jordan&amp;rsquo;s life, interests, and the stories and concepts that he pulled from to write The Wheel of Time. The second two thirds are just a glossary listing of people, places, and things. But only their linguistic derivation, not their significance to story or characters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learning a little about the linguistic derivations of names is fun, for example, Avalon becomes Tar Valon. Going super deep on those gets boring real fast. The problem is that while we learn 5 or 6 aliases for the name Lanfear, but don&amp;rsquo;t get the explainition of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; Lanfear gets so many different names. I&amp;rsquo;m also simply not impressed or interested with early English mythology, from which so much naming is pulled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-4-20-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-4-20-zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert Pirsig&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;☆ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quality is the measure of fitness for a particular purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There, I&amp;rsquo;ve solved it for everyone in a single sentence. The best thing you can possibly do is to stop reading now - stop reading this article, stop reading analyses of the book, and most certainly don&amp;rsquo;t read the book itself. It is an absolute waste of time. In 400 pages, Pirsig manages to get close to this solution exaclty once, on page 300-something (I just can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered with this book anymore&amp;hellip;)[1].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Peace War</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-3-18-the-peace-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-3-18-the-peace-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vernor Vinge&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Peace War&lt;/em&gt; is an absolute masterclass in classic Sci-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It starts with an unlikely hero, gives them a mentor and room to grow, puts them in increasing degrees of peril, and pulls the reader in with several twists that are just guessable enough that it compells you to keep reading faster and faster as you near the end. The characters and technology are grounded in enough science to make them very believeable, with the smallest suspension of disbelief required to understand the bobbles. The writing is direct but assumes a lot of the reader, requiring that you keep up with evolutions of in-world technology and strategy. This elevated requirement of mental agility is wonderful and makes you feel like your brain is working, not merely following along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lives of the Stoics</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-2-25-lives-of-the-stoics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-2-25-lives-of-the-stoics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ryan Holiday&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been practicing Stoicism for just a few years now, and probably like many, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the top quotes from the top Stoics: Marcus Aurelius, Seneca, Epictetus. But at some point in practice, one desires to learn more breadth of the history and enriched depths of characters that created it. &lt;em&gt;Lives of the Stoics&lt;/em&gt; serves that purpose wonderfully - it gives a roughly chronological overview of the main Stoic thinkers, their particular focuses within the philosophy, and examples of how they lived it in their lives. This is a great example of why secondary sources can indeed be useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Organized Mind</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-2-1-the-organized-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-2-1-the-organized-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Levitin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book opens extremely strong, with some of the author&amp;rsquo;s original neuroscience research, compounded with research from his peers, outlining a framework of thinking about the theory and purpose of organization as a concept, then as it can be applied to most of our everyday lives. It starts as a very academic read, which is both challenging and fun in a can-feel-your-brain-growing kind of way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone Is Unacceptable</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2025-1-19-the-iphone-is-unacceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2025-1-19-the-iphone-is-unacceptable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I do every 4-5 years, I got iPhone-curious today, and decided to write a letter to my future self for when it happens next time. Of course, Apple makes the best hardware, the best camera, and the best CPUs on the phone market today, but despite all those advantages, the current (16) iPhone is simply unacceptable for daily use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For such refined hardware, the human-ignoring design of the software is incredibly disappointing. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that Android gets all of these just right either, but it provides &lt;em&gt;options&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Superlatives</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-1-17-2024-superlatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-1-17-2024-superlatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024, I read 20 books, an increase from the 14 I read in 2023. Giving out superlatives last year and ranking my favorites was rather fun, so although I don&amp;rsquo;t have a photo of all the physical books because I read many on kindle, here&amp;rsquo;s the new list -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tress of the Emerald Sea&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Nightfall&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ghost Town Living&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Neverwhere&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Slow Productivity&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Atomic Habits&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Ride of a Lifetime&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Krondor Assassins&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Krondor Tear of the Gods&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Krondor Betrayal&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jimmy and the Crawler&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mona Lisa Overdrive&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yumi and the Nightmare Painter</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-1-10-yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2025-1-10-yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first book I finished in 2025 has a real chance of being the best book I read in 2025. &lt;em&gt;Yumi and the Nightmare Painter&lt;/em&gt; is simply a masterclass in writing characters that grow, demonstrate emotion, and have wonderful interpersonal connections. Both Yumi and the Nightmare Painter grow because they push each other, but also pull each other up when they need help. This doubles as some mental health therapy if the reader is so inclined to apply a lesson or two to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rabbits</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-11-8-rabbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-11-8-rabbits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Terry Miles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently, I&amp;rsquo;m a total sucker for VR puzzles and mysteries that spill over into the real world. &lt;em&gt;Rabbits&lt;/em&gt; captures the imagination in the same way as the beginnings of &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;. This concept of a puzzle that starts online but escapes through the imagination of its players into real life is just mesmerizing. Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s thrillers &lt;em&gt;The DaVinci Code&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Digital Fortress&lt;/em&gt; are fun for the same feel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Body Problem</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-11-three-body-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 23:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-11-three-body-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cixin Liu&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;☆ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t even come close to understanding how this book won the Hugo award. Not only is it boring and difficult to follow in cultural translation, but it gets so many scientific facts wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s on these demerits that I shall rip the book apart. The Hugo medallion on the cover is the only reason I not only finished reading it, but then didn&amp;rsquo;t throw it directly in the trash. These myriad cross-discipline technical inaccuracies warrant my first 0-star rating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-2-atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:44:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-10-2-atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;James Clear&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Atomic Habits easily gets 5 stars from me, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why it continually tops bestseller lists. It&amp;rsquo;s a fast and fun read with compelling and concrete examples. As I&amp;rsquo;m sure it was designed to, it inspires the reader to start working on new habits and recognize that their true power will be apparent only after the accumulation of a great many rounds of practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Jesuit Guide to (Almost) Everything: A Spirituality for Real Life</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-26-jesuit-guide-to-almost-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 22:57:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-26-jesuit-guide-to-almost-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;James Martin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is a slog. It took weeks of forcing myself to return to it, and 400 pages to say nothing over and over again. The entire premise is that your life is better if you are &amp;ldquo;nearer&amp;rdquo; to God. &amp;ldquo;Nearness&amp;rdquo; is roughly defined as things that make your life &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; is roughly defined as defined as being everywhere, in all things and thoughts, and the solution to all issues. I found this nearly 100% nebulousness nearly 100% unhelpful and impractical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking to Work in the Rain</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-28-walking-to-work-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 20:28:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-28-walking-to-work-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I get to walk somewhere in the rain. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s just into the office at work, or into the grocery store. But a few minutes outside in the rain can be a wonderful time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not like driving where you&amp;rsquo;re warm and comfortable and insulated from the rain itself and only have to manage the windshield wipers. Walking in the rain let&amp;rsquo;s you experience a natural wonder no matter where you live. It&amp;rsquo;s free and easy and can be spectacular &lt;em&gt;if you choose to let it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tress of the Emerald Sea</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-14-tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 23:03:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-9-14-tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tress&lt;/em&gt; is easily one of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s best books, only &lt;em&gt;Mistborn&lt;/em&gt; is in the same category. It combines a smart hero who learns and grows along the way with a fantastically new magic system (only 1/3 of which gets explored, sequals here we come!), incredibly witty dialogue, and a storyline that never feels slow or stale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the main strengths of &lt;em&gt;Tress&lt;/em&gt; the excellent characters and their dialogue; it&amp;rsquo;s realistic, snarky, and witty in the style of Good Omens, which Sanderson actually mentions as an inspiration in the author&amp;rsquo;s notes at the end of the book. But Tress was &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Evolution of Language</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-4-skibidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 21:10:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-9-4-skibidi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a whole class of internet-based complaints about the current language used by, I think, middle schoolers of the moment. These complaints center around both newly invented words and existing words that have been assigned new meanings, interchangable with their old forms. The small-minded complainers take their outrage over these &amp;ldquo;brainrot&amp;rdquo; words to the internet, while the rest of us, if you&amp;rsquo;ve even heard a Gen-Alpha talk lately (I certainly haven&amp;rsquo;t), simply ignore them in the normal time-tested tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy and the Crawler</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-30-jimmy-and-the-crawler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 23:04:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-30-jimmy-and-the-crawler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing necissarily &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;remarkable&lt;/em&gt; about this book, and that&amp;rsquo;s perfectly fine. Fans of Jimmy the Hand will thoroughly enjoy a return to Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s street-smart antics ranging from Krondor to Kesh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no Asimov Twist at the end like many of Feist&amp;rsquo;s books, but I&amp;rsquo;m still angry about the character he killed, and especially at the way it happened. I begrudgingly suppose that means the writing was immersive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frugal Wizard&#39;s Handbook for Surviving Medieval England</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-15-frugal-wizards-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 23:03:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-8-15-frugal-wizards-handbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book generally stinks. One of the large fatal flaws is usually a strength for Sanderson - the magic system of &amp;ldquo;boasts&amp;rdquo; consists of, as best I can tell because it&amp;rsquo;s not ever really explained, weird poems about how the boaster is great. The other, and totally disconnected, magic comes from the actions of wights who kindly perform exactly the correct task at exactly the correct time, for small offerings of fruits and nuts. Even if I personally didn&amp;rsquo;t care for this magic system, it&amp;rsquo;s not really explained or even demonstrated enough to get the reader a comfortable understanding of the system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mona Lisa Overdrive</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-30-mona-lisa-overdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 22:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-30-mona-lisa-overdrive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;William Gibson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only lucid page of this book is the last, where Gibson somehow pulls an amazing Asimov Twist from the wreckage of a great many useless characters, their useless locations, and nonexistent relationships. Of the 2 stars here, 1 of them is awarded to my own imagination for coming up with an amazing world that is sort of written about in the book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no discernable purpose to any of the 4 completely separate and disjointed storylines, none of which have any sort of climax or resolution, just a bunch of things that happen. Goes on too long with no tightening of threads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krondor: Tear of the Gods</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-20-krondor-tear-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:50:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-20-krondor-tear-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another great book starring Jimmy the Hand. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure anything can compare, for me, to spending the summer before 6th grade playing one of the earliest computer RPGs, and certainly the first 3D RPG I had played. But the book does a fair job of condensing an entire game into a shorter readtime than playtime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most interesting difference is the lack of immersion the book version provides. In a game where you&amp;rsquo;re driving the story forwards, there&amp;rsquo;s both real risk and reward associated with putting on armor that might be cursed or blessed, or a ring that might be poisioned. You might be able to identify a potion as Fire Oil and use it to great combat advantage, or you might need to risk drinking an unkown elixer hoping that it&amp;rsquo;s a health potion. You might be disappointed when all the rubies you recover turn out to be fakes, and you might be frustrated when it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly difficult to put the shipwrecker&amp;rsquo;s wind puzzle back together before it fades away. Some of those same experiences made it into the book&amp;rsquo;s story, but only for the reader to be &lt;em&gt;told&lt;/em&gt; that Jazhara was frustrated at the locked puzzle; you don&amp;rsquo;t take it personally the same way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krondor: The Assassins</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-10-krondor-assassins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:57:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-7-10-krondor-assassins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best part of this book is the character building. I know the characters of &lt;em&gt;Return to Krondor&lt;/em&gt; well, and this gives deeper backstory and color to all of them, and others. Jimmy the Hand&amp;rsquo;s quick thinking and cleverness stars in both game and books, but we also get first hand stories of Arutha&amp;rsquo;s wisdom both in battle and court. We meet William for the first time and get to know a young soldier learning his place and forming his viewpoint. Captain Treggar, who could easily have been a throwaway character, gives a smart and practical example of managing yourself in relation to others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krondor: The Betrayal</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-30-krondor-betrayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 18:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-30-krondor-betrayal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The definition of a solid fantasy book without being a absolute smash hit. It&amp;rsquo;s a good book; just go read it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, this book was based on the Video Game &lt;em&gt;Betrayal at Krondor&lt;/em&gt;, which I did not play, but sets up the plot for &lt;em&gt;Tear of the Gods&lt;/em&gt; which is based on &lt;em&gt;Return to Krondor&lt;/em&gt;, a game that I played the absolute heck out of the summer before 6th grade (1999). &lt;em&gt;Return to Krondor&lt;/em&gt; was thoroughly formative in defining what many parts of I consider a good video game, and I still quote it often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Stoic Joy</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-6-30-a-stoic-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 18:37:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-6-30-a-stoic-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of what I write is about books - I enjoy reading and learning from the lessons inside their stories. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing an observation, really just a perspective of the world I chanced upon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last week in the Pocono Mountains, a rural and picturesque area of Pennsylvania sprinkled evenly with one-street coal towns and million-dollar resorts. The National Competition for the dance year is the main event; bottom-tier contestants cry as they run off stage after receiving an Elite Gold medal, and the best are awarded Premier Battle of Champions Crystal Trophies, Golden Tickets, Banners, and Pins. Competition is a place of extremes, where the extreme bottom starts at the natural top, and the adulations always ascend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ride of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-18-the-ride-of-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 21:45:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-18-the-ride-of-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert Iger&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is awesome because Iger talks about why things were hard, what he did to face the difficulties, and why those choices led to him being successful. He uses examples to color the ideas with story that draws you in, and neatly summarizes those ideas in ways that flow and teach. If you read this book through once and make an earnest attempt to learn anything from it, you&amp;rsquo;ll be a dozen leadership steps ahead of a certain billionaire I worked for (2022-2024).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ocean at the End of the Lane</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-1-the-ocean-at-the-end-of-the-lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 21:09:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-6-1-the-ocean-at-the-end-of-the-lane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My best description for this book is that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;American Gods&lt;/em&gt; about kids. Most likely not &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; kids, unless the kids you know enjoy being terrified of all sorts of things being weird and wrong. I think the correct genre label for this book is actually horror. It thankfully didn&amp;rsquo;t give me nightmares or get me jumpy, but I know myself enough to know that I don&amp;rsquo;t care for horror; I&amp;rsquo;d rather experience something else. This is probably my least-favorite Gaiman book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neverwhere</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-18-neverwhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 22:18:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-18-neverwhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nobody writes hallucinations like Neil Gaiman; to my judgement, he&amp;rsquo;s the undisputed master. &lt;em&gt;Neverwhere&lt;/em&gt; is another wonderful example of this ability, and takes the reader on a fast, weird, and wonderful journey into the opposite of a normal, common, place. That weirdness is exactly what makes the book so readable and enjoyable - you feel both comfortable with the common, but excited to see it in a new light.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow Productivity</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-11-slow-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 22:17:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-5-11-slow-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, the negatives, because there are few. The writing in this book is dry and academic, with the structure making it feel like you&amp;rsquo;re reading a series of 5-paragraph-essays from elementary school It tells instead of showing, and that slows the cadence of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, the message is both incredibly effective and simple:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Do fewer things.&#xA;&#xA;Work at a natural pace.&#xA;&#xA;Obsess over quality.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;While those rules along could be enough, the bulk of the book is a pleasent discussion on the historical framework, where we went wrong, and how to fix it. I do wish there were more, or deeper, real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something Exciting</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-5-6-something-exciting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 22:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-5-6-something-exciting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a huge amount of SciFi recently, and wanted to try writing my own original story with a brand new idea and an Asimov-style twist at the end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joe opened his lunchbox and let the metal lid clink down on the workbench. Peanut butter and jelly, again. Certainly better than he had eaten during much of his time at the university, but not quite as exciting as he might wish for. Just like the job itself, he supposed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Princess Spy</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-27-the-princess-spy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 21:57:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-27-the-princess-spy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Larry Loftis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;☆ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DID NOT FINISH, RECYCLED&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book successfully tricked me into trying it by using the word &amp;ldquo;Spy&amp;rdquo; in the title, but thouroughly failed at being readable shortly thereafter. The &amp;ldquo;spy&amp;rdquo; part of the book is glossed over rapidly, the protagonist attending CIA training and becoming an expert in thrilling skills such as firearms, encryption cyphers, and avoiding other agents, all in about 4 pages. The rest of the book dives deep into her feelings, especially surrounding a CIA-training-classmate whom she falls in love with instantly and for no reason. She then travels to Spain for spy work, where she falls in love with (of course) the most famouse Matador in the world, also for no reason. Until her first love from CIA training shows up in Spain unannounced. And that&amp;rsquo;s when I realized this book is a romance and has nothing to do with spies or WWII.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holy Moments</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-28-holy-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 21:57:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-28-holy-moments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matthew Kelly&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book&amp;rsquo;s severe simplicity brings the readability down to, in my estimation, around an 6th grade level. The writing is pretty lackluster and boring, but the core messages are actually very solid. It just takes far too many pages to say too little about these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Holy Moments&amp;rdquo; are first defined as when someone chooses to take a Good action instead of a Bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Town Living</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-10-ghost-town-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 22:23:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-4-10-ghost-town-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brent Underwood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is a great fast and fun read, regardless of your familiarity with Brent&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel about living in Cerro Gordo. If you are already familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look behind the scenes into some of the details and off-camera hard work it has taken to start rebuilding a ghost town.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By far my favorite thing about the book however, is that Brent actually demonstrates what it looks like to live life as a Stoic. While many helpful sources talk about how the ancient Stoics thought about the world, or what a Stoic &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do in theory, Brent shares stories about how this philosophy has actually influenced his life in major ways. Rebuilding the Yellow Grade Road, rebuilding the American Hotel, rebuilding a writer&amp;rsquo;s cabin, and rebuilding a water source each present both obstacles, and the way forward when you frame your own perspective correctly. Small and sometimes subtle shifts in this personal perspective have given him the mental fortutude to face significant challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything a Moonshot</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-4-2-everything-a-moonshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 23:30:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2024-4-2-everything-a-moonshot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What if everything was a moonshot?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nobody remembers anything small, so why do we bother? Small changes rarely have the desired impact, because we have compromised before ever starting the project. When we accept that doing &amp;ldquo;just this part&amp;rdquo; will be good enough, we are actively saying that we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; indeed see the big picture, but don&amp;rsquo;t believe that either it&amp;rsquo;s possible or worthwhile to accomplish it. Given that it&amp;rsquo;s not worthwhile to accomplish the big-picture ask, should we even be attempting the scaled-down version?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sofware Developer&#39;s Career Handbook</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-18-the-sofware-developers-career-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 17:01:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-18-the-sofware-developers-career-handbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Lopp&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book suffers from an unfortunate case of being a product of a very specific time and set of circumstances. Moving from waterfall to agile, lunchtime card games, all-staff meetings, and working weekends to &amp;ldquo;ship&amp;rdquo; are all bygones in 2024. Originally written 10 years ago and just now supposedly updated then repackaged, the book does not hold up. Concrete lessons are few and far between, with the most helpful sections focusing on identifying the personalities of different players in the corporate game. Lopp&amp;rsquo;s best insights come from the fact that once you identify those personalities, then their motivations, then their intentions, then their plays, then you can be one or more steps ahead of them and make situations into wins for yourself. He also makes a very compelling case for how lying at work is awesome, everyone is doing it all the time, you should lie too, and even more importantly, you should learn to figure out when others are lying to you. The most salient point is that you should have a career plan: what work do you want to be involved in, who do you want to work with, and how are you going to manage yourself into those positions. Work with intent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating My Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-3-19-automating-my-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-3-19-automating-my-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on 2021-3-19 as an internal tech blog post when I was the Tech Lead for Wayfair&amp;rsquo;s Experimentation Platform team. Internal links will not work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;automating-my-mistakes&#34;&gt;Automating my mistakes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While building the initial steps of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.csnzoo.com/shared/gambit-task-queue&#34;&gt;GTQ&lt;/a&gt; project I found mysef stuck without a way to test code locally (at least without standing up a lot more project environment scaffolding), meaning that I had a slightly longer than ideal change/test loop:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Profiling with Python</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-1-26-python-memory-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2021-1-26-python-memory-profiling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on 2021-1-26 as an internal tech blog post when I was the Tech Lead for Wayfair&amp;rsquo;s Experimentation Platform team. Internal links will not work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-i-learn-about-memory-profiling-in-python&#34;&gt;Where I learn about memory profiling in Python&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve observed that Simulations can fail when run in Kubernetes pods. We suspect the reason is that these pods are under-resourced and are running out of memory, then being killed/restarted by Kubernetes in order to keep the overall cluster healthy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nightfall</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-5-nightfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 23:43:47 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-2-5-nightfall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Isaac Asimov&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most impressive aspects of Asimov&amp;rsquo;s writing is that it can change your worldview in just a few pages of a short story. When the twist at the end makes you rethink how the universe works, the writing comes alive off the page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Nightfall anthology is great for 2 reasons. It covers a huge range of topics, styles, and story sizes. It also features a quick message from Asimov himself before each story, with his perspective on writing that story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Superlatives</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-1-25-2023-superlatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 22:48:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2024-1-25-2023-superlatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time, probably ever, I think I actually own all the books I read in the previous year. So while I enjoy ranking books, among other things, doing it physically is a fun twist!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./2024-1-25-2023-Superlatives.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;/2024-1-25-2023-Superlatives.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I had to place a dividing line, I&amp;rsquo;d put only the top 4, The Deep Range and above, into my &amp;ldquo;highly recommended&amp;rdquo; list for the year. I&amp;rsquo;m proud of myself for trying such a wide range of books, but in the future I would rather increse the percentage of books that I really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think Like a Monk</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-17-think-like-a-monk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 22:58:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-17-think-like-a-monk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jay Shetty&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book took me probably 6 months to finish. I picked it up several times, but struggled to find it interesting enough to finish and frequently moved on to a new book. I would have greatly preferred to simply read stories about Shetty&amp;rsquo;s time in the ashram, and how he applies those lessons to modern life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It sits at the intersection of productive self-improvement and philosophy, so ostensibly a very interesting subject. Indeed, a few excellent points are made, and the similarity between India&amp;rsquo;s Bhagavad Gita and Roman Stoicism is absolutely striking. The more philosophy I study, the more I come to believe that any personal reasoning system must be a reflection or view of Stocism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-12-the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 22:22:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-12-12-the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ursula K. LeGuin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book really sucks. Mostly for the completely wasted opportunities of fairly good ideas. A world too cold for insects and animals larger than a dog to survive, yet with still active volcanic zones. People who are both genders. Explorers from worlds light years away making contact with primitive humans and bringing them into a universal community. Actually, that last one had a documentary about it called Stargate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Slow Regard of Silent Things</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-30-the-slow-regard-of-silent-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 07:50:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-30-the-slow-regard-of-silent-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-slow-regard-of-silent-things&#34;&gt;The Slow Regard of Silent Things&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Rothfuss&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to start listening to any book that opens with &amp;ldquo;You might not want to read this book.&amp;rdquo; The problem is that I really did want to read this book, or at least the story that I thought it would be great if it contained. I wanted to read about how Auri came to be who she is and live where she does, and why her view of the world is shaped the way it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wise Mans Fear</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-11-the-wise-mans-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 22:10:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-10-11-the-wise-mans-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-wise-mans-fear&#34;&gt;The Wise Man&amp;rsquo;s Fear&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Rothfuss&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I read Fantasy and Sci-Fi books, I like to take note of particular writing methods and distill them into themes that can be harnessed when doing my own writing. These themes of course can be split into &amp;ldquo;emulate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;avoid&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;The Wise Man&amp;rsquo;s Fear&lt;/em&gt; is gracious enough to provide one of each.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In-Universe Complex Context Reload&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting off with the &amp;ldquo;emulate&amp;rdquo; column, as a sequal, this book is responsible for bringing you back into Kvothe&amp;rsquo;s world of the Four Corners. In particular, the magic system of &lt;code&gt;sympathy&lt;/code&gt; requires a bit of context loading for the reader. This is accomplished very smoothly, and better yet, inside the story itself through character discussion. I&amp;rsquo;m proud of realizing this is what was going on only part way through that scene, since it felt entirely natural and not contrived to fit the purpose. This is in contrast to &lt;em&gt;The Lost Metal&lt;/em&gt; which has another relatively complex magic system, but neglects to refresh the user on the mechanics of how it works. You&amp;rsquo;re thrust directly into using the magic, without any refresher on the particulars. This might work better for a faster-paced medium like TV where you&amp;rsquo;re likely to watch several episodes or even the whole series in quick succession. But in books, where even at Brandon-Sanderson-pace it&amp;rsquo;s likely for sequals to be released with years between, gentle reminders of complex systems seems to work very well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Name of the Wind</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-9-16-the-name-of-the-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:15:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-9-16-the-name-of-the-wind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-name-of-the-wind&#34;&gt;The Name of the Wind&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Rothfuss&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At almost 700 pages, this is far from the longest book I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read, but I read it faster than some books 1/3 it&amp;rsquo;s size. Perhaps an even greater compliment is the several times I stayed up hours late reading to finish the story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story itself is actually nothing all that earth-shattering: our hero is orphaned as a young boy, learns hard lessons on the street, finds himself clever enough to make it to the magical University, and then excells in lessons, while causing a fair amount of trouble. The story strikes me as a more logical and fully-developed version of Harry Potter, without all the plot armor. Significant things actually go wrong and derail the hero&amp;rsquo;s journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Omens</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-8-30-good-omens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:05:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-8-30-good-omens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;good-omens&#34;&gt;Good Omens&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman and Terry Pratchett&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never been the antagonist of a book before, but it turns out to be pretty fun. When a logical argument can be made for the representatives of both Heaven and Hell to work together because the real problem is those pesky humans, the result is a golden story. The best part is that the relationship between an angel and demon turns out incredibly naturally, perhaps because they both borrow so much of their personalities from those same flawed humans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Metal</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-25-the-lost-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:11:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-25-the-lost-metal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lost-metal&#34;&gt;The Lost Metal&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brandon Sanderson&#xA;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reading this book strongly reinforces the importance of approaching a series in order, and ideally without interruption. In this case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t, and the experience suffered for it. I had read the first book in the series, unknowingly skipped the second two, and picked up this book as the 4th because I knew I enjoyed the author and series. The problem is that significant plot points and items are discussed as if they are common knowledge, because to the characters they are, but I had to piece them together with very limited context clues. In a way, this is similar to the idea of having an ideal amount of invented terms, but those are more likely to be heavily contextualized and therefore add to the story. Elements from previous stories being treated as commonplace results in somewhat the opposite effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-1-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 21:55:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-7-1-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;red-team-blues&#34;&gt;Red Team Blues&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cory Doctrow&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is a fun, quick, and entertaining read, but the best part is that it&amp;rsquo;s a techno-thriller that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get anything wrong. Although this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the accomplishment that it is, not getting any technical details wrong really is quite notable. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly complaining that an author decided to include detail they didn&amp;rsquo;t need to, and then got some part of that detail wrong. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a huge amount of detail in the tech elements, but it does manage to explain cryptocurrency correctly while maintaining the story&amp;rsquo;s immersion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disney Engineered</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-8-20-disney-engineered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 20:52:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-8-20-disney-engineered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2023-8-20-Disney-Engineered-Pic1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;2023-8-20-Disney-Engineered-Pic1.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides world-class entertainment, immersive story-driven rides, and fine dining where you can eat filet mignon 3 times a day [1], the engineered efficiency of Disney World is absolutely top-tier. That makes it all the more fun to find situations that can be improved. Our most recent trip in August 2023 provided a few:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to enter the parks, you must scan either an RFID-based MagicBand(TM) which is like a digital watch without all the excitement, or an RFID-based card, which is like a Disney-branded RFID card. Disney has correctly anticipated that the park entrance lines will be extremely busy, especially during park opening, and has therefore placed 2 RFID scanners at the head of every entrance line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviathan Wakes</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-6-12-leviathan-wakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:09:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-6-12-leviathan-wakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;leviathan-wakes&#34;&gt;Leviathan Wakes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James S. A. Corey&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure out why this book was 600 pages long.  There&amp;rsquo;s not a huge amount of action, intrigue, and certainly not suspense.  Oh, except that GRRM blurbed the cover and the proles think he&amp;rsquo;s the only fiction author to ever exist, despite ample evidence that he&amp;rsquo;s both a terrible and lazy writer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Characters and places are described directly, but in the wrong sort of way.  &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re an idealist.&amp;rdquo; one will say to another, without the reader having seen proof of such previously.  I guess we&amp;rsquo;re just supposed to believe whatever the latest character says out loud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overpacking</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-5-20-overpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 22:41:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-5-20-overpacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do we like overpacking for trips so much?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s because the brain loves resets and new things - I think the brain actually loves &lt;em&gt;getting good&lt;/em&gt; at new skills and environments much more than it enjoys &lt;em&gt;being good&lt;/em&gt; at those same skills and in those same environments.  The brain is near infinitely flexible and that&amp;rsquo;s its ultimate strength.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just finished packing for a single weekend away.  I wanted to bring a journal and necessary fountain pen, writing prompt book, a new nonfiction book to read, handheld amateur radio, laptop, camera gear, and Nintendo Switch.  I stood over my already full bag thinking &amp;ldquo;wow, this sure is a great time to pick back up all these activities that I love&amp;rdquo;.  When in reality, I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched any of those for weeks if not months at home.  So what&amp;rsquo;s the immediate necessity of bringing all those toys for a weekend away when I haven&amp;rsquo;t even prioritized using them where they &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; need to be lugged around in a suitcase?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Park</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-4-30-jurassic-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:54:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-4-30-jurassic-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;jurassic-park&#34;&gt;Jurassic Park&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Michael Chrichton&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I somehow made it through the 90s without ever seeing &lt;em&gt;Jurassic Park&lt;/em&gt; the movie, so when I found a paperback copy of &lt;em&gt;Jurassic Park&lt;/em&gt; the book at the Northborough Library Book Sale, I figured this was my opportunity to do it the right way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read the book first, then watch the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always known that dinosaurs are just about the coolest creatures ever, and Tyrannosaurus king among them.  I&amp;rsquo;ve stood in awe of fossil skeletons of T. Rex in Washington D.C. (MOR555), and New York City (AMNH5027), as well as replications of SUE (FMNH PR2081) both in Boston and Disney&amp;rsquo;s Animal Kingdom.  Including replications, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen 10% of the discovered T. Rex fossils, which is pretty awesome. [1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Sniper</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-3-15-american-sniper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:53:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-3-15-american-sniper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;american-sniper&#34;&gt;American Sniper&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chris Kyle&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some subjects are always worth learning about, even if they&amp;rsquo;re not personally interesting, generally interesting, or have any redeeming qualities whatsoever.  These subjects demand at least some attention from any learned mind, even if the only lessons are in their awfulness, responsibility, or consequences.  A few books about the Holocaust come to mind, especially &lt;em&gt;Night&lt;/em&gt; by Eli Wiesel.  There is nothing good about the subject, but learning and understanding it teaches the reader about an awful part of the world so that we may understand and avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Deep Range</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-30-the-deep-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:53:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-30-the-deep-range/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-deep-range&#34;&gt;The Deep Range&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arthur C. Clark&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is classic Sci-Fi at it&amp;rsquo;s best - a plucky protagonist with a few more smarts and skills than average takes on a new mission, a mission that he succeeds at in fact, until the pivotal brain-bending twist that forces you to step back and think &amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This &amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo; moment is my favorite thing about Sci-Fi, and to me, the facet that defines it.  While most of the world feels familiar, although time and technically advanced, the extra leap of faith completely breaks the reading experience, pulls you out of the story, and leaves you considering the repercussions still days later.  This sort of profound experience is amazing fun; I&amp;rsquo;ve found it in a few other places: &lt;em&gt;Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game&lt;/em&gt;, and first watching &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agency</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-15-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:05:55 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-15-agency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;agency&#34;&gt;Agency&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;William Gibson&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of books with lots of overly-specific brand names where the protagonist is just along for the ride, only participates by presence, and does nothing to affect their own outcome in the story, then boy howdy this book is for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Lives of Color</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 23:04:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-2-5-the-secret-lives-of-color/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-secret-lives-of-color&#34;&gt;The Secret Lives of Color&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kassia St Clair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think I read this book incorrectly.  I approached it in the usual manner; starting at the front, making progress one page at a time, until all pages have been turned in order.  Progress was measured in groups of 10-20 pages, covering the stories of 2-5 individual colors at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are other valid methods however, and it seems a wise reminder to not automatically approach every scenario with only the exact techniques that have worked in the past.  Far better is to build a toolbox of skills, and know when to deploy each one to it&amp;rsquo;s greatest effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Other 8 Hours</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-1-10-the-other-8-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 23:03:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2023-1-10-the-other-8-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a quote that I can neither exactly remember nor find [1], in which some terribly heretical 19th-century socialist extolls the absurdity of limiting a work day to 8 hours, they also comment on the remaining 8 hours of leisure, rest, and relaxation time that each man has available at the end of the workday, and before the biologically required 8 hours of sleep. The main point is that every man is free to conduct himself exactly like the wealthy for those 8 hours. No matter the man&amp;rsquo;s station at work, or the fact that he must work at all to provide for his family, in those remaining 8 hours, equality is governed by self-directed purpose. He might study the fine arts of literature and painting, attend theater, or study philosophy. In the &amp;ldquo;other 8&amp;rdquo; hours, there is no limit to the type of self-improvement a man is allowed to undertake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadow of a Dark Queen</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:42:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2023-1-7-shadow-of-a-dark-queen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;shadow-of-a-dark-queen&#34;&gt;Shadow of a Dark Queen&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Serpentwar Saga is off to an unfortunate start: we follow a mercenary company as they sail around for a bit, march here, march over there, march up those mountains, march back down the slightly easier other side of the mountain, march into a town, march out of a town, march into a meeting of companies, march away from the other companies, march through a strange magical tunnel that turns out to have absolutely no bearing on the story&amp;hellip;  There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of adventuring around in order to learn the super secret important information, but when the mission is completed, we&amp;rsquo;re not even included on what the secret info was.  On the plus side, at the very end, lots of things explode, and there&amp;rsquo;s a spectacular use of battle magic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ender&#39;s Game</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-enders-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-enders-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Orson Scott Card&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game does several sci-fi-book things correctly. The setup requires you to suspend disbelief, invented terms are used well, and the story continues after the climax to a satisfying result that is both an ending and a possible sequel setup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good sci-fi book asks the reader to suspend disbelief about some, possibly very important, statements given as facts. The story beginning with Ender as a six-year-old makes no sense whatever, especially when his voice and actions would be a better match for a mature 20-something. However, accepting this early start allows for an important payoff at the end of the book when Ender still needs to see the world through a child&amp;rsquo;s eyes. Realizing the trick that was played on Ender a few pages before he did was immensely satisfying and made those next pages absolutely fly by. It is curious however, that even with all his brilliance, Ender himself does not realize until the game is over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into the Wild</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-into-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-into-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Krakauer&#xA;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The writing is fine. The storyline of the book is fine. What&amp;rsquo;s not fine is Chris McCandless&amp;rsquo;s lame vagabondry - a series of poorly-at-best thought through decisions can be defended only by the ambiguous &amp;ldquo;call of the wild&amp;rdquo;. Despite several starting advantages in life, McCandless decides to spend his life on the road for no reason other than a desire for &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; that only he can understand yet cannot express or communicate to others. This life on the road is then poorly executed; McCandless apparently makes no attempt to learn wilderness realities, craft, or survival techniques, either in theory or practice. This is the story of a obnoxiously amateur self-annointed expert. While most of us do indeed self-annoint some amount of expertise during college before learning better, McCandless&amp;rsquo;s carelessness removes his ability to learn from his mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prince of the Blood</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-prince-of-the-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-prince-of-the-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;br&gt;&#xA;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You could equally hand this book to a new reader of high fantasy or to a longtime fan of the genre and the Riftwar, and they would both be impressed and excited throughout the length of the story. Focusing on Prince Arutha&amp;rsquo;s sons journey to Kesh and their own maturity, Jimmy the Hand takes a significant supporting role as mentor and conspirator of Arutha&amp;rsquo;s stunning last-page twist. Through the Riftwar so far, we&amp;rsquo;ve never had much first-person insight into Arutha&amp;rsquo;s mind, but this cliffjump implies so much for the reader to think about once the printed words are finished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REAMDE</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-reamde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-9-3-reamde/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neal Stephenson&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DID NOT FINISH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The score of &amp;ldquo;DID NOT FINISH&amp;rdquo; is reserved for books so incredibly offensive that completing them is a net negative on time investment. Rarely is it possible to have your intelligence &lt;em&gt;reduced&lt;/em&gt; by reading, although certain books make the possibility clear. I made it to page 139 out of 1044 (13.3%).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;REAMDE&lt;/em&gt;, Stephenson falls into, in my opinion, the most basic mistake a writer, especially of science fiction, can make: insisting on an incredibly detailed world and then getting those details wrong. By far the better authorial choice would be to follow Asimov or Gibson&amp;rsquo;s examples by zooming out when describing scenes from the imagination:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronauts Guide to Life on Earth</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-astronauts-guide-to-life-on-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-astronauts-guide-to-life-on-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chris Hadfield&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ★&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I read nonfiction, instead of taking notes in the moment, I take a picture of the salient passage and transcribe them later. The stories Commander Hadfield shares are incredibly interesting and well told, but the sheer number of pithy lessons that I found myself returning to undoubtedly rank this book very highly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Preparation:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my experience, fear comes from not knowing what to expect and not feeling you have any control over what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen. When you feel helpless, you&amp;rsquo;re far more afraid than you would be if you knew the facts. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what to be alarmed about, everything is alarming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coraline</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-coraline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-coraline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ★ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt;, in the great way that Neil Gaiman excells at. Thouroughly enjoyable, I read this over the course of two afternoons. Some years ago, I spent days reading &lt;em&gt;American Gods&lt;/em&gt; - and although they are both weird in a similar and excellent sort of way, &lt;em&gt;Coraline&lt;/em&gt; was a much faster, simpler, experince, and refreshing for it. Elements of the simplicity and directness that quickly advance the story are strong positive influences that I&amp;rsquo;ll use for myself in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Minimalism</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-digital-minimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-digital-minimalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book builds on the consistent themes of Professor Newport&amp;rsquo;s work - that in our new attention economy, your time is your most precious resource, and protecting it from digital distractions is exceedingly and increasingly difficult, because millions of the smartest mind-hours are devoted to depriving you of it for their own profit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In defense of this onslaught, high-quality leisure undertaken solely for the satisifaction of it&amp;rsquo;s completion provides a significant mental fortress. Solitude and itentional practice of using digital tools for a singular purpose further remove the mind from increasingly assumed-standard distractions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dune Messiah</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-dune-messiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-dune-messiah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ☆ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing really happens in this entire book. Paul Maud&amp;rsquo;Dib antagonizes himself with the ability to see the future, yet somehow do nothing about his own predestination. Instead of a storyline, the book skips around to follow the fleeting thoughts of several characters and their current feelings towards one another; the definition of a Space Opera, in the worst way. The conflict is stated instead of shown, and the fascinating future-historic technology of &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; is almost entirely missing. Existing in the same universe as the excellent &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; entirely fails to be a redeeming quality of this sequel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy the Hand</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-jimmy-the-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-jimmy-the-hand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond E. Feist&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s signature cleverness is used to great effect both causing and getting out of trouble in a series of adventures, where the reader gets to know more inner workings of the Thieves Guild. A parallel storyline details events touched upon in the main Riftwar Saga. This is the main drawback of the book; Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s adventures are second to none, yet half the book is spent following others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Peripheral</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-the-peripheral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-24-the-peripheral/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;William Gibson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The protagonist of this book is a bystander to the story, and to a minor character&amp;rsquo;s conflict. She does nothing to advance the story, and barely participates in it. This is either one of the greatest examples of &amp;ldquo;being nothing but a pawn in a game for higher beings&amp;rdquo;, or a very disjointed way of telling a story; I&amp;rsquo;m very much not sure which is true. The dystopian futurism feels at times ominously achievable, and at others, narrowly focused on insignificant themes. The last two chapters feel tacked on in order to berate the reader with two of the extrordinarily few salient and moral points. The ending where everything works out perfectly is supremely boring, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the dystopian setting of the rest of the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-6-apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/book-reviews/2022-8-6-apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I sit down to write this, logging into Goodreads with a Facebook account hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked for 12 days. That seems like a fairly insane timeframe for an outage of this magnitude. But it also shows something else important. Amazon doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about Goodreads. Although that&amp;rsquo;s probably been obvious to the site&amp;rsquo;s users for some time, this puts a number on how low the priority stack ranking goes. After all, what percetage of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business is books anymore?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Emoji of Data</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2019-1-26-oneemojiofdata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spent some time thinking about how nice it is to be able to pay for gas a with a phone app from inside the car, the get out and start pumping immediately, no card swiping or buttons besides the big 89 needed.  And once you&amp;rsquo;re done pumping, the app collects one single point of feeback data: you can click either the Smile, Meh, or Frown emoji.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, something is being done with this data.  And hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;s useful analysis that is eventually incorporated into improvements and higher returns for the business.  On the surface, one emoji worth of data isn&amp;rsquo;t that much and it might be pretty tough to understand anything about user experience with one solitary data point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Inspiration from a Gas Station</title>
      <link>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 01:02:03 -0405</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vjacek.github.io/writing/2018-2-25-designinspirationfromagasstation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, Cumberland Farms has transformed themselves from a blue-and-orange gas station that you go to because you have to, into a blue-and-green (because you can reap the marketing rewards of &lt;em&gt;the color green&lt;/em&gt;) gas station destination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They did all this by changing the few things that people actually care about when it comes to gas stations.  The stations now have a bright, modern design, with white walls and light wood floors.  Their shelves are consistently well stocked, and they are even &lt;em&gt;clean&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
